# **Resume of Rubiyat Hasan Siddik**

#### Contact details:

Contact no: +8801625571559

Mailing Address:

House: 22, Road-05, Shialbhari, Mirpur, Dhaka-1216 Email: <u>rubiyat21@gmail.com</u>, Skype: rubiyat.rumi

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/rubiyat-hasan-siddik-421612147



With my 3 years of IT experience in Software Development and Web Application Development. Using Java SE, Java EE, Spring, Object Oriented PHP, Codelgniter, Laravel.

Experienced in various business application areas like – Point of Sale, Idea collection System and Forum Discussion, Production Management, School Management System, Library Management System, Budget and transaction system, Management Information System, Blog, Content management system and Job Searching application.

I also have experience to lead a team with members of three programmers and complete project successfully.

Throughout my professional career, I have been developing business applications whether it is web based or desktop application including Web/Windows Services. I have been exercising Java and PHP platform for development using Java SE, Java EE, Spring, Object Oriented PHP, Codelgniter, Laravel technologies for business layer development. For presentation layer I have been using HTML 5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JQuery/JavaScript, Ajax, vue.js. To develop the back-end development, I used mainly MySql. I also have experienced in Agile Methodology to develop software.

# **Technical Profile Highlights**

#### Language:

HTML, HTML 5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JQuery/JavaScript, Ajax, vue.js, Angular js, Java SE, Java EE, Object Oriented PHP, Codelgniter, Laravel, Jaspersoft, JSP, Servlet

#### **Development Tools**

NetBeans, Eclipse, Sublime Text

#### **Database**

MySql.

#### **Technologies**

Spring Framework, JDBC

# **Design Tools**

Microsoft Visio

# **Employment History**

A. Company: Cluster Informatics

Position held: Software Programmer

Period: 01 Nov 2016 - 30 April 2018

# Responsibilities:

• Work under the supervision of a team lead.

- Carry out tasks assigned by team lead.
- Taking full responsibility of the assigned task.
- Maintaining systems by monitoring, identifying and correcting software defects.

B. Company: Win-Win Service Provider Position held: Software Engineer

Period: 01 May 2018 - 30 June 2018

#### Responsibilities:

- Work under the supervision of a team lead.
- Carry out tasks assigned by team lead.
- Taking full responsibility of the assigned task.

C. Company: ATI Limited

Position held: Junior Programmer

Period: **01 July 2018 – 30 November 2019** 

## Responsibilities:

- Work under the supervision of a team lead.
- Carry out tasks assigned by team lead.
- Taking full responsibility of the assigned task.

# **Educational History:**

## **Graduation:**

# **Bachelor in Business Information Technology**

University of Greenwich, UK

Session: 2017-2018

# Diploma:

- International Advanced Diploma in Computer Studies National Computing Center, UK
- International Diploma in Computer Studies
   National Computing Center, UK
- International Foundation Year in Computer
   Studies National Computing Center, UK

# **HSC (Higher School Certificate):**

# **Higher Secondary Certificate**

Dhaka Commerce College, Dhaka Board GPA 4.90 out of 5 (Commerce stream)

Session: 2010-2011

# SSC (Secondary School Certificate): Secondary School Certificate

Rupnagar Model School & College, Dhaka Board GPA 4.94 out of 5 (Commerce stream)

Session: 2008

# **Certification Training and Course**

 Advanced Javascript from Udemy License Number: UC-63D54A8T

Certification URL: http://ude.my/UC-63D54A8T

2. Angular 5 (formerly Angular 2) - The Complete Guide from Udemy

License Number: UC-H2FHPXCZ

Certification URL: <a href="http://ude.my/UC-H2FHPXCZ">http://ude.my/UC-H2FHPXCZ</a>

3. PHP with Laravel for beginners - Become a Master in Laravel from Udemy

License Number: UC-6VATQ2UD

Certification URL: <a href="http://ude.my/UC-6VATQ2UD">http://ude.my/UC-6VATQ2UD</a>

4. Database Design and Management from Udemy

License Number: UC-MYELQNI6

Certification URL: http://ude.my/UC-MYELQNI6

5. Learn How To Build a Web Application Without Coding from Udemy

License Number: UC-N4VNKKCZ

Certification URL: <a href="http://ude.my/UC-N4VNKKCZ">http://ude.my/UC-N4VNKKCZ</a>

6. The Java Spring Tutorial: Learn Java's Popular Web Frame from Udemy

License Number: UC-LI8G6XFN

Certification URL: http://ude.my/UC-LI8G6XFN

7. Building An E-Commerce Store Using Java Spring Framework from Udemy

License Number: UC-OJFD7WFV

Certification URL: http://ude.my/UC-OJFD7WFV

8. JSP, Servlets and JDBC for Beginners: Build a Database App from Udemy

License Number: UC-JJ7FWPBP

Certification URL: <a href="http://ude.my/UC-JJ7FWPBP">http://ude.my/UC-JJ7FWPBP</a>

9. PHP OOP: Object Oriented Programming for beginners + Project from Udemy

License Number: UC-GGQDMY2I

Certification URL: http://ude.mv/UC-GGQDMY21

10. JavaScript for Beginning Web Developers from Udemy

License Number: UC-24A58PDK

Certification URL: http://ude.my/UC-24A58PDK

11. PHP for Beginners - Become a PHP Master - CMS Project from Udemy

License Number: UC-8PLD5ISY

Certification URL: http://ude.mv/UC-8PLD5ISY

12. Java Programming Language Java SE 6 from IBCS-Primax Software Bangladesh

Ltd.

License Number: 50277320

13. Responsive Web Design – Lite from Udemy

License Number: UC-B7Y728KX

Certification URL: <a href="http://ude.my/UC-B7Y728KX">http://ude.my/UC-B7Y728KX</a>

14. Wordpress 101 Course from Udemy License Number: UC-SUTMV5VZ

Certification URL: http://ude.my/UC-SUTMV5VZ

- 15. APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT IN ANDROID from Bdjobs.com
- 16. PHP PROGRAMMING WITH CODEIGNITER FRAMEWORK from Bdjobs.com
- 17. Natural Writing from S@ifur's

# **Online Programming Test**

CSS Test (Old), Taken on Sep 2013, Score: 3.50 out of 5, Conduct by: upwork Description: This test is about 50 multiple choice questions and should take less than 40 minutes to complete. This test is taken by upwork. It is a upwork CSS (Cascade Style Sheet) Test for web designer.

- 1. 2D, 3D and Animation 100%
- 2. Basic Styles 80%
- 3. Basic User Interface 80%
- 4. Color Styles 100%
- 5. Font Styles 67%
- 6. Fundamentals 56%
- 7. Page Media 75%
- 8. Selectors 60%
- 9. Speech and Ruby 100%
- 10. Text and Style Attribute Syntax 33%

XHTML 1.0 Test, Taken on Sep 2013, Score: 3.40 out of 5, Conduct by: upwork Description: this test is about 50 multiple choice questions and should take less than 40 minutes to complete. This test is taken by upwork. It is a upwork XHTML Test.

- 1. Fundamentals 50%
- 2. Images and Links 86%
- 3. Tables and Forms 78%
- 4. Tags 64%

## **Project History:**

## 1. e-Idea

# **Project Summary:**

Our system name is e-idea. This is a web application and it's a role based secure ideas collecting system. Idea submission and manage submitted idea are the main objectives of this system. Our team has four members and we develop this system through team work. Each member of this team performed a specific role to develop this system. We have successfully developed this system by following agile scrum methodology. This system meet all given requires and also added some extra features to make this system more user friendly. I was performing programmer and web designer role in this team. So I had managed both sides of technical and design aspect of this system.

# Responsibilities:

- 1. UI Designer.
- 2. Programmer of this application.

# Technologies & Languages:

I haved used HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap for design frontend or interface. I will also Javascript, Jquery and Ajax to make this application more interactive. I will use php framework name laravel to develop this application. In this project use chart.js for presenting data through graph.

#### Database:

I have used mysql database to store all information of this application.

## 2. ghs

## **Project Summary:**

This Application is for Gazipur High School. The full meaning of ghs is Gazipur High school. It is a School management Application. As this management system will be centralized, the chances of the duplicate data in the system are close to nil. The automation feature of this management system will mitigate the task of writing the papers. E.g. there is no need to write the report card of the students on the paper by the pen. It is simply can be done online on the system, and can be forwarded to the students and their parents. In today's rush hour of life, it is difficult for a parent to go to the school of his / her child every time a teacher calls. By this management system, it will be easier for a parent and a teacher to be in touch every day. As a matter of fact, it will be easier for each individual person who is associated with the system to be in touch as per needed.

#### Responsibilities:

- 1. UI Designer.
- 2. Programmer of this application.

# Technologies & Languages:

I haved used HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap for design frontend or interface. I will also Javascript, Jquery and Ajax to make this application more interactive. I will use php framework name laravel to develop this application. Here i have used datatable and chart.js for presenting data through graph.

#### Database:

I have used mysql database to store all information of this application.

# 3. Printing Production

# **Project Summary:**

It is a desktop software. This software is for Golden Rain Design Company to manage their production line. This software provides them to keep their printing design, order details, sample details information. This provides opportunities to maintain their stock through this software. So that they can maintain their sock materials such as printing colors, chemicals, printing instruments. This software provides them a function to tracking production stage. So that the owner can easily know the stage of production and able to ensure his client about product. Software can keep information about client and workers. This software provides report on per hour production, per day production, unit cost and also per day income and month end income. So that they can know about company statues and can able to take action in the right time.

# Responsibilities:

- 1. Requirement Analysis
- 2. Design full system architecture.
- 3. Create database architecture design.
- 4. Design User interface.
- 5. Write Java SE code for all features.

## Technologies & Languages:

In this software used Java language to develop and used Java swing to draw user interface for this system. I have used jespersoft for reporting.

#### Database:

I have used mysql database to store all information of this application.

# 4. Simple POS

## **Project Summary:**

This project is a very popular and widely used in many big supermarket / departmental stores and is used to cater the need of the sales system there. This is a desktop software and is used to maintain / control most of the activities happening in big stores. This maintains and controls the stock details and does billing and generates reports.

## Responsibilities:

- 1. Requirement Analysis
- 2. Design full system architecture.
- 3. Create database architecture design.
- 4. Design User interface.
- 5. Write Laravel code for all features.

## Technologies & Languages:

In this software used Java language to develop and used Java swing to draw user interface for this proposed system. I have used jespersoft for reporting.

#### Database:

I have used mysgl database to store all information of this application.

#### 5. Job

# **Project Summary:**

This is a web application named Call2Job where skillful and none skillful person can find their suitable one time job. A job provider also can find a skillful and none skillful employee according to his one time job requirement for a specific job by this application. Here a job seeker can be an Electrician, plumber, driver, teacher etc. Job provider can be anyone. A job seeker will pay for using this application but it is totally free for job providers. This application works like a medium to communicate with each other between one time job seeker and job provider.

### Responsibilities:

- 1. Requirement Analysis
- 2. Design full system architecture.
- 3. Create database architecture design.
- 4. Design User interface.
- 5. Write Laravel code for all features.

# Technologies & Languages:

I haved used HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap for design frontend or interface. I will also Javascript, Jquery and Ajax to make this application more interactive. I will use php framework name laravel to develop this application.

#### Database:

I have used mysql database to store all information of this application.

## 6. Library-management

## **Project Summary:**

Library management system is a web application that manages and stores books information electronically according to user's needs. The system helps both users and library manager to keep a constant track of all the books available in the library. It allows both the admin and the user to search for the desired book. It becomes necessary for the library to keep a continuous check on the books issued and returned and even calculate fine. This task if carried out manually will be tedious and includes chances of mistakes. These errors are avoided by allowing the system to keep track of information such as issue date, last date to return the book and even fine information and thus there is no need to keep manual track of this information which thereby avoids chances of mistakes.

Thus this system reduces manual work to a great extent allows smooth flow of library activities by removing chances of errors in the details.

## Responsibilities:

- 1. Design full system architecture.
- 2. Create database architecture design.
- 3. Design User interface.

- 4. Write Laravel code for all features.
- 5. Reporting for admin and users

# Technologies & Languages:

I haved used HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap for design frontend or interface. I will also Javascript, Jquery and Ajax to make this application more interactive. I will use php framework name laravel to develop this application.

#### Database:

I have used mysql database to store all information of this application.

#### 7. Portfolio

# **Project Summary:**

This project is a web application. User can dynamically add his/her resume through this application. User can dynamically add menu, his/her education, expertise, skill etc. It has very user friendly and robust system. It is very easy to use and very attractive design.

# Responsibilities:

- 1. Requirement Analysis
- 2. Design full system architecture.
- 3. Create database architecture design.
- 4. Design User interface.
- 5. Write Laravel code for all features.

# Technologies & Languages:

I haved used HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap for design frontend or interface. I will also Javascript, Jquery and Ajax to make this application more interactive. I will use php framework name laravel to develop this application.

#### Database:

I have used mysql database to store all information of this application.

# 8. Drug International

# **Project Summary:**

This application develop for a drug company name drug international limited. It is a content management system. By this application user can manage and show their drug details, company content and production related information in their website for their potential customers. User can change language as company also has business in China so user can change full website content in English and chainess. User can search drug by generic, by brand. The full website is dynamic and it control by this content management system.

#### Responsibilities:

- 1. Design User interface.
- 2. Develop some features and functionality.
- 3. Fixing bug
- 4. Testing full application

## Technologies & Languages:

For developing this application I have used HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap for design frontend or interface. I will also Javascript, Jquery and Ajax to make this application more interactive. I will use php framework name codeigniter to develop this application.

#### Database:

I have used mysql database to store all information of this application.

#### 9. Palliative Care

## **Project Summary:**

This application develop for Palliative care hospital. It is a content management system. User manage their content and their service by this application. Palliative care spread their activities, service, aim, mission and vision through this content management system.

# Responsibilities:

- 1. Design User interface.
- 2. Develop all features and functionality.
- 3. Fixing bug
- 4. Testing full application

# Technologies & Languages:

For developing this application I have used HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap for design frontend or interface. I will also Javascript, Jquery and Ajax to make this application more interactive. I will use php framework name laravel to develop this application.

#### Database:

I have used mysql database to store all information of this application.

# 10. Universal Salt Iodization Program

# **Project Summary:**

This project is a web based management information system (MIS). The owner of this project is UNICEF. This application has multiple type of user and they can access the system as their role wise. It also maintain salt production, slat sale and salt sock. This application maintain all mill and their alt production, sale and stock. This application produce different kind of reports month or year wise.

## Responsibilities:

- 1. Lead a developer's team
- 2. Design User interface.
- 3. Develop all features and functionality.
- 4. Testing the application

## Technologies & Languages:

For developing this application I have used HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap for design frontend or interface. I will also Javascript, Jquery and Ajax to make this application more interactive. I will use php framework name laravel to develop this application.

#### Database:

I have used mysql database to store all information of this application.

# 11. Department Of Agricultural Extension

# **Project Summary:**

This project is web based budget and transaction application. It is a Bangladesh government project. This application maintain fund which comes from different sources. Then user can create budget from this fund. After that user allocate fund for all cost center. Cost center get fund and expense this fund by financial year wise. This application generate different kinds of financial and general report for the authority.

## Responsibilities:

- 1. Design User interface.
- 2. Develop all features and functionality.
- 3. Develop reporting section
- 4. Testing full application

# Technologies & Languages:

For developing this application I have used HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap for design frontend or interface. I will also Javascript, Jquery and Ajax to make this application more interactive. I will use php framework name laravel to develop this application.

#### Database:

I have used mysql database to store all information of this application.

# **Language**

- Bangla
   Full professional proficiency
- English
  Full professional proficiency

# **Personal Strengths:**

- Interested in creative work
- Interested to learn with technology
- Quick adaptation with new technology

# **References:**

- Abu Bakar Siddik
   Cluster Informatics (Founder Member)
   Vienna, Austria
   +43676848863681
- Zafar Iqbal, PhD
   Freelance Editor (Expert Reviewer)
   Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

## **END**